Ahmed Samir Elgendy

Senior Full Stack .Net Developer Senior Trainer – MCSD & MCSA W.A. 4 Years Experience Military Status : Exemption
Mobile : 01158350092

E-mail : Elgendya160@gmail.com.
Address : 12, El Matarawy street,

Elmatarya, cairo 11714

Egypt.

Highlight

Hi, I am ahmed samir, +4 Years Experienced Dotnet Developer with a demonstrated History of working in ERP systems. Skilled in C#, OOP, Databases, Design Pattern, Architecture, Front End Development and OOAD. Strong information technology Professional with a graduate studies degree focused in computer science from faculty of Graduate studies for statistical research (FSSR), Cairo University

Education

Degree : Postgraduate diploma in computer science (2018).

University : Faculty of statistical studies and research (FSSR) - Cairo university.

Grade : Very-Good.

Degree : Bachelor of computer science (2016).

University : Thebes academy.

Grade : Excellent.

GraduationProjects

Degree	Project Name	Main Project features	Languages and tools
Postgraduate Diploma	Educational services system for fssr-Cairo university	 Student can register his/her academic account Student can browse his/her profile, passed courses Student can register his/her academic courses also can evaluate both teacher and courses Teacher can store degrees for student after exams 	 Html, css, bootstrap and jquery C#, asp.net MVC Jtable ajax control Sql server Visual studio 2015 MS sql server 2014
Bachelor	Developing electronic and mobile responsive student management system	 Admin can create new student, course, stuff, labs and exam schedules. Student can browse his/her profile, Passed courses, remaining courses and final degrees Student can register his/her academic course 	 Html, css, bootstrap and jquery C#, asp.net MVC Sql server Visual studio 2015 MS sql server 2014

Language Skills

Arabic : Mother tongue. English : Very Good.

Technical Skills

Languages, Technologies and other Skills:

- Object oriented analysis and design (OOAD)
- Working with Business Analysis (BRD SRS Mockups)
- Working with Software Methodologies (Scrum Sprint Agile)
- Object oriented programming (OOP)
- C#.NET, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Core
- Web APIs (Create Call Test Document Security)
- Sql server, T-SQL, LINQ, Entity framework, Entity framework Core.
- Working with Code First and Database First.
- Acceptable knowledge with Design Pattern, Unit Of Work, Repository Pattern,
 3-Tier Architecture, N-tier Architecture and Onion Architecture.
- Reporting services (SSRS).
- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, Bootswatch, Materialize, JQUERY UI, JQUERY Plugins.
- JAVASCRIT, JQUERY, Typescript, Angular 11
- Working with controls such as (Ag-Grid, Telerik, JTable, Prime ...etc)
- Working with UI Templates and admin dashboards (Admin LTE, BSB Admin)
- Working with Version Controls (TFS Git Hub)

Tools:

- Microsoft Visual Studio 2019, Microsoft Sql server 2014, Sql report builder 3.0.
- Visual Studio Code, Postman, Swagger

Work experience

Senior Full Stack .NET Developer. (Currently)

TE Data (WE)

- Review code that written by other developers.
- Manage plans and tasks.
- Working with development phases.

Senior Full Stack .NET Developer. (2018 - 2020)

El-Malaz Software Solutions.

- Manage Team Tasks and Effort Through TFS.
- Analyzed and documented business applications requirements from clients.
- Developed and Implemented back end tasks through work environment.
- Worked with reusable applications to enhance performance and user experience.

Software Engineer. (2017 - 2018)

Bonian Tech. Software Solutions.

- Analyzed and documented business applications requirements from clients.
- Developed and Implemented back end tasks through work environment.
- Assisted in systems analysis and design.

Senior Full Stack .NET Developer. (2016 - 2017) eBSEG Solutions.

- Developed and Implemented back end tasks through work environment.
- Assist with R&D Team for new technologies integrations.

Computer science Lecturer

Thebes academy

Present academic courses

MCSD + MCSA (web application) Free Lancer Trainer For The Following Courses #70480, #70483, #70486, #70487 At :

- NEN Global
- Senior Steps
- IT Share
- CLS
- Sharp Academy
- Reload

Projects

MCIT Portal (Local Network at Ministry)

• This application manage internet service orders in ministry of communication

HRMS (http://hr.gmtcc.co/)

 Hr System that manage all employee affairs such as (Attend and leave, Personal cycle, vacation and absence, recruitment, payroll)

Elsarh ERP System (Local Network at KSA)

• Real estate system manage purchases, sales, bills, Inventory.

Legal Affairs system for the Ministry of Manpower (http://mom.manpower.gov.eg/)

Converted all manual recording tasks at ministry to system.

All World Reservation (http://www.awr-travel.com/)

Free Lance Website

• Hotel and room reservation with online payment and CMS dashboard

Speed Org. (http://speedorg.net/)

Free Lance Website

• Basic web site dynamic pages with CMS admin dashboard

$Pyramids \ Creative \ (\ \underline{\textbf{Github:}} \underline{\textbf{https://github.com/Egy-Coder/LastPyramid}}\)$

Free Lance Website

• Basic web site dynamic pages with CMS admin dashboard

Morgan Group (Domain Expired)

Free Lance Website

• Basic web site dynamic pages with CMS admin dashboard